Register of the Leonid Pavlov papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Leonid Pavlov papers
1989-2004
2009C32
Hoover Institution Archives
4 manuscript boxes (1.7 linear feet)
Correspondence, minutes, protocols, reports, circulated material, and financial records relating to activities of the independent trade union Nezavisimost' in the Soviet Union and post-Soviet Russia.
Pavlov, Leonid.
Nezavisimost'.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items, computer media, and digital files. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos, films, or digital files during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2009.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Leonid Nikolaevich Pavlov, a Russian political activist from Saint Petersburg, was involved in establishing independent trade unions and independent political and trade union publications during and immediately after the collapse of the Soviet system.
Scope and Content of Collection
The Leonid Pavlov papers consist of correspondence, minutes, protocols, reports, circulated material, and financial records relating to activities of the independent trade union Nezavisimost' in the Soviet Union and post-Soviet Russia.
The original folder titles given by the creator have been maintained. Within individual folders, materials have been kept in their original order as accumulated by the creator.
Labor movement--Soviet Union.; Labor movement--Russia (Federation)
- File 1, 1989-2002
  - Kniga registratsii otdelenii Nezavisimosti, 1989-1993 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Kniga ucheta postupleniia i otpravleniia delovykh pisem profsoiuza Nezavisimost', 1990-2002 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - Podborka materialov nekotorykh pervukh otdelenii i struktur Nezavisimosti, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - Dogovory i kontrakty Nezavisimosti, 1990-2001 (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - Grazhdanskii fond sodeistviia zaniatosti Nezavisimost', 1991-1992 (Box-folder 1: 5)
- File 2: Vkhodiashchaia perepiska Nezavisimosti, 1989-2004 (Box-folder 1: 6-7)
- Files 3-4: Iskhodiashchaia perepiska Nezavisimosti, 1991-2004 (Box-folder 1: 8-12)
- File 5: Ustavy i metodicheskie materialy, 1989-1998 (Box-folder 2: 1-3)
- Files 6-7: Materialy redaktsii gazety Za nezavisimost', 1991-1998 (Box-folder 2: 4-6)
- File 8: Raznoe, 1989-1995 (Box-folder 2: 7)
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes "Akt o neschastnom sluchae na proizvodstve" and other office papers.
- File 9: Profsoiuz: bank, 1997-2001 (Box-folder 2: 8-9)
  Includes account statements from the Bank Saint Petersburg.
- File 10: Redaktsiia: bank, 1998-2002 (Box-folder 2: 10-11)
- File 11: Kassa profsoiuza, 1995-2003 (Box-folder 2: 12-13)
- File 12: Kassa redaktsii gazety, 2001-2004 (Box-folder 2: 14, Box-folder 3: 1)
- File 13: Fiksirovannoe sostoianie fiinansov, 1996-2000 (Box-folder 3: 2)
- File 14: Dvizhenie finansov, 1996-2001 (Box-folder 3: 3)
- File 15: Protokoly sovmestnykh sobranii Peterburgskogo IKARa-"Nezavisimost'" i redaktsii Rossiiskoi biulleten'-gazety Za nezavisimost', 1991-2004
  - 1991 (Box-folder 3: 4)
  - 1993 (Box-folder 3: 5-8)
  - 1994 (Box-folder 3: 9-10)
  - 1995 (Box-folder 3: 11-12, Box-folder 4: 1)
  - 1996 (Box-folder 4: 2-3)
  - 1997 (Box-folder 4: 4-5)
  - 1998 (Box-folder 4: 6-7)
  - 1999 (Box-folder 4: 8-9)
  - 2000 (Box-folder 4: 10)
  - 2001 (Box-folder 4: 11)
  - 2002 (Box-folder 4: 12-13)
  - 2003-2004 (Box-folder 4: 14)